<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Fedora | Welcome to Pandora's Box]]></title>
  <link href="http://hustcalm.me/blog/categories/fedora/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://hustcalm.me/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-12T13:03:26+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://hustcalm.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lihang Li]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Build PTAM on Fedora 20 the easy way - 10 Minutes Tutorial]]></title>
    <link href="http://hustcalm.me/blog/2014/04/17/build-ptam-on-fedora-20-the-easy-way-10-minutes-tutorial/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-17T19:21:41+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://hustcalm.me/blog/2014/04/17/build-ptam-on-fedora-20-the-easy-way-10-minutes-tutorial</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been a while since the last post <a href="http://hustcalm.me/blog/2013/09/27/ptam-compilation-on-linux-howto/">PTAM Compilation on Linux-HowTo</a> about playing with PTAM. And now Isis Innovation has released the source code under GPLv3 and put it on <a href="https://github.com/Oxford-PTAM/PTAM-GPL">Github</a>.</p>

<p>Last time, we demostrate detailed instructions on how to get PTAM running on Debian derived systems(Linux Mint 15 and Ubuntu 12.04), now I want talk about building the source code on Fedora 20. It won&rsquo;t be long, since I just want to talk about the key components, thus the mandatory dependencies(<strong>TooN, libCVD, Gvars3, OpenGL, libjpeg, libpng, libtiff</strong>, etc).</p>

<!--more-->


<p>As the PTAM source code use the GNU autoconf tools, so the typical way to install is <code>./configure &amp;&amp; make &amp;&amp; sudo make install</code>, however, to make sure that certain third libs are correctly configured and can found when running <code>configure</code>, you may want to have a look at the output after <code>configure</code> and install any key dependency which is missed.</p>

<p>Whenever you are not sure, see the <strong>Official Website</strong> for sure!!!</p>

<h2>Install Dependencies</h2>

<h3>TooN</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.edwardrosten.com/cvd/toon.html">TooN</a> is a numerics library used by libCVD. Since they are just a bundle of header files, installation is trivial.</p>

<pre><code>sudo yum install liblapack-devel
sudo yum install libblas-devel

./configure &amp;&amp; make &amp;&amp; sudo make install
</code></pre>

<h3>libCVD</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.edwardrosten.com/cvd/">libCVD</a> is a very portable and high performance C++ library for computer vision, image, and video processing.</p>

<p>This is the key component for building PTAM, thus should be careful. Make sure you installed OpenGL correctly, also for the video source, if you are using a UVC webcam, check if <code>v4l2</code> is working. Or if you are using a IEEE1394 camera, get libxx1394 series libs installed which can drive your camera. For Image I/O, always have libjpeg, libpng and libtiff.</p>

<p>See the output after running <code>configure</code> and ensure all the options related are OK.</p>

<pre><code>sudo yum install freeglut-devel

./configure

make

sudo make install
</code></pre>

<h3>GVars3</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.edwardrosten.com/cvd/gvars3.html">GVars3</a> is a configuration library which integrates well with TooN. Not much to worry when buiding.</p>

<pre><code>./configure &amp;&amp; make &amp;&amp; sudo make install
</code></pre>

<h2>Build PTAM</h2>

<h3>Run ldconfig</h3>

<p>The libs built above may reside in <code>/usr/local/lib</code> when using the default directorys in their Makefiles, to make the system aware of the newly installed libs.</p>

<pre><code>sudo vi /etc/ld.so.conf
add /usr/local/lib to the file
sudo ldconfig
</code></pre>

<h3>Prepare for Makefile</h3>

<pre><code>cd the_PTAM_Directory
cp Build/Linux/* .
vi Makefile
add -lGLU -lGL -llapack to the linker commands
</code></pre>

<h3>Fix usleep declaration</h3>

<pre><code>vi Tracker.cc
add #include &lt;unistd.h&gt; to the first line
</code></pre>

<h3>Build</h3>

<pre><code>make
</code></pre>

<p>If nothing wrong, you are done!</p>

<h2>Run PTAM</h2>

<p>Simply invoke <code>CameraCalibrator</code> to calibrate your camera. Then invoke <code>PTAM</code> for real fun.</p>

<p>If you use UVC webcam using <code>v4l2</code>, you may want to install:</p>

<pre><code>sudo yum install v4l-utils
</code></pre>

<p>Use <code>v4l2-ctl</code> to play with your camera.</p>

<h2>Trouble Shooting</h2>

<p>As the orinigal <a href="http://www.robots.ox.ac.uk/~gk/PTAM/README.txt">README.txt</a> says, PTAM works well with Nvidia display card, I got <code>Segmentation Fault as soon as ... got video source</code> as I&rsquo;m using a display card shipped with an Intel motherboard.</p>

<p>However, I think the root cause is that the display card driver does not know how to handle the color space coming from the webcam, so I&rsquo;m planning to deep into the mechanism and try to find out why. <a href="http://ewokrampage.wordpress.com/troubleshooting-faq/">George Klein</a> says that a nvidia display card and driver combo works fine after all.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[小记Fedora 19 Release Party和Barcamp Beijing August]]></title>
    <link href="http://hustcalm.me/blog/2013/08/24/xiao-ji-fedora-19-release-partyhe-barcamp-beijing-august/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-24T09:47:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://hustcalm.me/blog/2013/08/24/xiao-ji-fedora-19-release-partyhe-barcamp-beijing-august</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>离这两个活动已经过去一周的时间了，总觉得应该写点什么，那就以这篇“小记”来叙述吧。</p>

<p>Fedora一直以来被冠以edge bleeding的称号，尝鲜者的最爱，自己从Ubuntu 9.04开始使用Linux，便一直与其无缘，现在想想，确是有一些遗憾的（具体说不上来为啥，也许自己总是希望小众一些，Fedora在国内的用户确实不是太多，至少相比于Ubuntu来说是这样的，有限的CentOS使用经历告诉我，这是一款值得使用的Linux发行版）。Fedora 19,代号“薛定谔的猫”，作为第一款“原生”支持3D打印的操作系统，让人眼前一亮。</p>

<p>Barcamp对我来说则陌生很多，在活动的前两天才得知消息，告诉我的人说是“一个充满各种创意制作的聚会”，而实际上“这里是一个充满各种创意演讲的地方”。具体的信息，大家移步<a href="http://www.barcamp-beijing.com/">Barcamp官方网站</a>吧。</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Fedora 19 Release Party</h2>

<p>这次RP，主要有三个议题，涉及Cloud Computing，System Trace，3D Printing。</p>

<h3>OpenShift &amp; Cloud</h3>

<p>演讲人Gerard Braad（@gbraad），Fedora 大使委员会成员，亚太地区区域导师，Fedora社区和开源社区的活跃演讲者，致力于Fedora品牌的推广。</p>

<p>OpenShift算是一种PaaS，演讲者先是就虚拟化的一些基本概念进行阐述（虚拟化的分类，典型的技术，比如KVM，LXC等），再谈到OpenStack的基本架构，之后涉及OpenShift的架构。新的概念不多，而且讲解非常深入浅出，非常适合云计算入门。</p>

<h3>SystemTap Introduction</h3>

<p>演讲人Robin Lee（李瑞彬），供职于北京蓝汛 (ChinaCache)。在 Fedora 项目中是 packager 的角色，致力于提高自由软件的质量和整合度。</p>

<p>SystemTap 是 Linux 下的可编程的通用系统跟踪工具，可进行侵入式跟踪，可用于内核态和用户态跟踪及代码注入。在 Linux 实现了大致相当于 DTrace 的功能。其语法由 AWK 语言发展出来。本次分享主要介绍了SystemTap 的基本语法和一些使用举例，最后生成火焰图（Flame Graph）的例子还是很酷的。</p>

<p>这是个纯技术话题，不多说了，我比较好奇的是Trace实现的底层原理，在网上查了下，以下两篇文章很不错：</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://blog.csdn.net/wudongxu/article/details/6345481">systemtap原理及使用</a></li>
<li><a href="http://xuclv.blog.51cto.com/5503169/1184517"> linux系统分析工具续-SystemTap和火焰图（Flame Graph）</a></li>
</ul>


<h3>3D Printing at Fedora 19</h3>

<p>演讲人Tong Hui（@tonghuix），开源软件与开源硬件的布道者，开源嵌入式培训导师，GNOME 基金会成员，北京GNOME用户组成员。</p>

<p>这个演讲的信息量比较大，演讲者从3D打印机的历史开始说起，谈到了3D打印的现状以及常用技术，并且简单分析了技术实现，最后结合Fedora进行了真机演示（DFRobot公司的3D打印机）。</p>

<p>我的理解是，3D打印机是嵌入式技术，3维建模技术，材料学的完美结合！</p>

<h2>Barcamp Beijing August</h2>

<p>聚会地点在Microsoft Research Asia一层，主要参与人员是国际友人，国际友人的友人，还有众多的ABC。God，谁让他们的英语都那么native呢！</p>

<p>这一天比较大的收获是，体验了Barcamp的活动形式（Speech &amp; QA），见识了演讲者的无限魅力（I really mean it!），获取了一些“创新”思维。其它的觉得表达不出来了（因为在会上，有一种略微的不适感，难以融入到老外的圈子里面去），大家等下次Barcamp的时候自己去体会吧！</p>

<p>会不会有一天也在Barcamp上演讲？（Who TM knows，可能性不大，看自己了！）。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
