<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: SEO | Welcome to Pandora's Box]]></title>
  <link href="http://hustcalm.me/blog/categories/seo/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://hustcalm.me/"/>
  <updated>2021-01-20T00:19:40-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://hustcalm.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lihang Li]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Know Your Website Better Using Google Webmaster Tools, Analytics and Authorship]]></title>
    <link href="http://hustcalm.me/blog/2014/01/23/know-your-website-better-using-google-webmaster-tools-analytics-and-authorship/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-23T03:05:43-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://hustcalm.me/blog/2014/01/23/know-your-website-better-using-google-webmaster-tools-analytics-and-authorship</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I happened to get to know <code>Google Webmaster Tools</code>, <code>Google Analytics</code> and <code>Google Authorship Markup</code> when I try to tweak my <code>Octopress</code> website. Found that Google is really doing lots of interesting things for our websites, I will share some useful tips and links here.</p>

<hr />

<h3>Google Webmaster Tools</h3>

<p>Go to <a href="http://www.google.com/webmasters/">Official Webmasters</a> to get started, first try to look around to know what <code>Webmasters</code> aims to do. After that, login to <a href="https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools">Webmaster Tools</a> , add your website by clicking <code>Add Website</code>, then verify the website according to the hints.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>As long as you have claimed the owership of your website, you can see the dashboard for detailed information. You can submit your <code>sitemap</code>, see the <code>search query</code> statistics, the status of your website.</p>

<p>Explore more to find something more exciting:&ndash;)</p>

<p>To be more professional, see <a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/35769?hl=en">Webmaster Guidelines</a>.</p>

<hr />

<h3>Google Analytics</h3>

<p>Even better, <a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/">Google Analytics</a> will let you know every single click from users to your website. See <a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/features/index.html">Analytics features</a> for complete lists to know what <code>Analytics</code> can do. Initially set up for commercial use or marketing promotion, we can adapt this technique to our personal website.</p>

<p>Also, look carefully about <code>your website report</code>, I bet you will find something interesting. For developers, there are <a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/?csw=1">Developer Guides &amp; Reference for Google Analytics</a>.</p>

<hr />

<h3>Google Authorship</h3>

<p>Well, it would be cool to attribute the article or post to its author, <a href="https://plus.google.com/authorship">Google Authorship</a> is the one who helps.</p>

<p>See the professional article <a href="http://searchengineland.com/the-definitive-guide-to-google-authorship-markup-123218">The Definitive Guide To Google Authorship Markup</a> for details. To test if you have successfully set your authorship, use <a href="www.google.com/webmasters/tools/richsnippets">Google Structured Data Testing
Tool</a>.</p>

<p>As for me, I verified my authorship through my Email related to my domain bought from <a href="https://name.com">name.com</a>. Simple Enable <code>Email Service</code> through the domain dashboard, you can set up a forward Email for your owned domain Email address.</p>

<hr />

<h3>Google FeedBurner</h3>

<p><a href="http://feedburner.google.com">FeedBurner</a> is a service for <code>RSS</code> subscribe. It&rsquo;s flexible enough and ease your pain when switching domains.</p>

<p>After you add your blog to feedburner, it supports <code>RSS readers</code> by default. So if you want your readers to subscribe through their Emails, go to your feeds and click <code>Publicize</code>, then click <code>Email Subscriptions</code>, down the page to click <code>Active</code> to make the service alive.</p>

<p>See other tabs of your feeds, there are really lots of for you to tweak and play with.</p>

<hr />

<p>When you find blogging more interesting and part of your life, it&rsquo;s time to give an eye for your website status and traffic. I used to blog for just expressing myself, but now I also tend to write something that readers would enjoy.</p>

<p>Hope this post would get you to know with the Google tools that you can use and make you a better blogger:&ndash;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[为Octopress博客添加Flag Counter侧边栏]]></title>
    <link href="http://hustcalm.me/blog/2012/10/16/wei-octopressbo-ke-tian-jia-flag-counterce-bian-lan/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-16T11:19:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://hustcalm.me/blog/2012/10/16/wei-octopressbo-ke-tian-jia-flag-counterce-bian-lan</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>今天为自己的Octopress博客添加了访问者统计工具，<a href="http://www.flagcounter.com">Flag Counter</a>，如何获得代码请访问官网。   <br/>
拿到了代码后，添加到侧边栏，在custom/asides添加flag_counter.html，然后在_config.yml中开启即可，其中flag_counter.html的格式如下：</p>

<pre><code>      
&lt;section&gt;       
&lt;h1&gt;Flag Counter&lt;/h1&gt;       
Code you get from [Flag Counter](www.flagcounter.com)       
&lt;/section&gt;      
 
</code></pre>

<p>针对以上代码，还需要在_config.yml文件中添加一行：</p>

<pre><code>flag_counter: true  
</code></pre>

<p></p>

<p>为了在本博文中显示flag_counter.html的第一行和最后一行的开关语句，特意额外添加了一组<code>if Tag</code>，Markdown，囧～</p>

<p>因为，在<code>rake generate</code>的时候遇到了Liquid Exceptioon&hellip;解决方案参考了<a href="http://code.google.com/p/liquid-markup/source/browse/trunk/lib/liquid/block.rb?r=2">源码</a></p>

<p><strong>Enjoy your Flag Counter:)</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
